Osborne Family Papers
Osborne Family Papers
- Communications and writings
  - Writings
    - Osborne, Agnes (Devens)
      - Diaries
        - Vols. 25-26, 1882-1883 (Box 234)
        - Vols. 27-38, 1883-1895; 6 folders (Box 235)
      - Journals, 1881 (Box 235)
      - Notebook, "England and Her Colonies" (Vol. 39), 1887 (Box 235)
      - Verse, circa 1890 (Box 236)
    - Osborne, David Munson
      - Articles and essays
        - "The Exploits of Montrose", circa 1885 (Box 236)
        - "Five New States", circa 1885 (Box 236)
        - On Urban Improvement Societies, circa 1885 (Box 236)
      - Travelog on Scotland (Box 236)
    - Osborne, Eliza (Wright)
      - Articles and essays, miscellaneous, undated (Box 236)
      - Diaries (Vols. 45, 47), 1861-1894 (Box 236)
      - Journal, "On Travel in the Western United States" (Vol. 48), 1871 (Box 236)
    - Osborne, Jane Abbey
      - Diaries (Vol. 49), 1884 (Box 236)
      - Verse, 1884 (Box 236)
    - Osborne, John Hall
      - Miscellaneous, 1901-1904 (Box 236)
    - Osborne, Lillie (Raben-Levetzau)
      - Miscellaneous, circa 1965 (Box 237)
    - Osborne, Lithgow
      - Miscellaneous, 1902-1943 (Box 237)
      - Articles and essays
        - "Al Smith and the Drinking Wets", 1928 (Box 237)
        - "American Foreign Policy and Atlantic Union", 1950 (Box 237)
        - On Denmark, circa 1925 (Box 237)
        - "For a Finer Forest Preserve", 1959 (Box 237)
        - "The Importance of the Upstate Democracy", 1932 (Box 237)
        - "Is Wild Trout Fishing Doomed?" Outdoor America, 1940 (Box 237)
        - "New York State's Ski Trails", 1938 (Box 237)
        - "Science and Conservation", 1941 (Box 237)
        - "The Task of Norwegian Democracy," The Norseman, IV, 1946 (Box 237)
        - On Western Defense, 1942 (Box 237)
        - On Woodrow Wilson, circa 1925 (Box 237)
      - Diaries
        - 1904-1926 (Vols. 50-55), 6 folders (Box 237)
        - 1929-1953 (Vols. 56-60), 6 folders (Box 238)
      - Editorials, 1923-1942 (Box 238)
      - Journals
        - "Berlin Journal," volumes I-VI, 1914-1917; 6 volumes (Box 239)
        - "Berlin Journal", 1914-1915; extracts (Box 240)
        - U.S. to Australia, 1943 (Box 240)
        - U.S. to Norway, 1944 (Box 240)
        - Norway to U.S. (Vol. 63), 1946 (Box 240)
    - Osborne, Thomas Mott
      - Miscellaneous, 1900-1925 (Box 240)
      - Articles and essays
        - On Abraham Lincoln, undated (Box 240)
        - "American Ideals", undated (Box 240)
        - On Balzac, undated (Box 240)
        - "Bazebalfevre", undated (Box 240)
        - "A Bit of Colored Glass!", undated (Box 240)
        - On Capital Punishment, 1924-1927 (Box 240)
        - "The Corporations vs. the People", undated (Box 240)
        - "Democracy and Education", undated (Box 240)
        - "Democracy and the Tariff", undated (Box 240)
        - On the Democratic Party in New York, circa 1910 (Box 240)
        - On Dissent in Wartime, 1895 (Box 240)
        - On Germany's Participation in World War I, circa 1920 (Box 240)
        - "Harry Bolasky, Pickpocket", circa 1920 (Box 240)
        - "Harry Klein, Gangster", circa 1915 (Box 240)
        - "The Harvard Graduate", undated (Box 240)
        - "Has the Democratic Party a Future?", 1908 (Box 240)
        - "Has the Prison Failed?", undated (Box 240)
        - "Italians and Poles", undated (Box 240)
        - "Jack Dropper", undated (Box 240)
        - On Lawyers, undated (Box 240)
        - On Letter Writing, 1896 (Box 240)
        - "In the Light of the New Penology", undated (Box 241)
        - "In Memory of Grace Hopkinson Eliot", 1924 (Box 241)
        - On Municipal Reform, circa 1905 (Box 241)
        - "My Friends: The Thieves and Burglars", 1915 (Box 241)
        - On the Mutual Welfare League, 1913-1915 (Box 241)
        - "The Origin of the Canoe", undated (Box 241)
        - On Penology, undated (Box 241)
        - On Politics, undated (Box 241)
        - Prison Discipline and Character Building, 1916 (Box 241)
        - "Our Prison System and a Suggestion", undated (Box 241)
        - "The Prison of the Future", 1516; drafts (Box 241)
        - "The Prison of the Future", 1916; galley proof and pamphlet (Box 241)
        - "Prison Reform in England", undated (Box 241)
        - On the Public Service Commission of New York State, 1907-1909 (Box 241)
        - On the Schwitovosky Affair, undated (Box 241)
        - "A Sketch of the Life and Character of David Munson Osborne", undated (Box 241)
        - On Susan B. Anthony, circa 1901 (Box 241)
        - "The Syndicate, the Law and the People", 1907 (Box 241)
        - On Theodore Roosevelt, circa 1904 (Box 241)
        - On Thomas Carlyle's Visit to a Model Prison, undated (Box 241)
        - "To A. W. M.", undated (Box 241)
        - "A True Basis of Wales", undated (Box 241)
        - "The True Foundation of Prison Reform", 1915 (Box 241)
        - "The True Issues for 1900" (Box 241)
        - On Voting, undated (Box 241)
        - On Wagner's Flying Dutchman, 1900 (Box 241)
        - On Washington Irving, undated (Box 241)
        - "What is the Democratic Party", undated (Box 241)
        - "What Shall the Perplexed Voter Do?" The Ethical Record, II, 1900 (Box 241)
        - "Who is to Get the Millions?", undated (Box 241)
        - "William Lloyd Garrison", undated (Box 241)
      - Autobiography, circa 1921; notes (Vol. 64) (Box 241)
      - Books, fiction
        - An American Dreyfus Case, undated; table of contents (Box 241)
        - A Tangled Web, undated; chapter I (Box 241)
      - Books, nonfiction
        - Adventures of a Green Dragon
          - Holograph, fragment, 1908 (Box 241)
          - Bound (Vol. 65), 1908 (Box 242)
        - Politics and Prisons, circa 1926; 4 folders (Box 359)
          Original typescript. Chapters are in a different order from the following draft. First folder includes a note from Mott's great-grandson and an annotated table of contents, mapping original chapter names to new chapter names.
        - Politics and Prisons, circa 1926
          - Miscellaneous notes (Box 242)
          - Table of Contents (Box 242)
          - Forward (Box 242)
          - I "The Road Camp," drafts A-C, 3 folders (Box 242)
          - II "The Decision," drafts A-B, 2 folders (Box 242)
          - III "Warden of Sing Sing" (Box 242)
          - IV "Sing Sing Prison," drafts A-B, 2 folders (Box 242)
          - V "The First Day," drafts A-C, 3 folders (Box 242)
          - VI "The Golden Rule Brotherhood" (Box 242)
          - VII "Progress Within" (Box 242)
          - VIII "The Sing Sing Courts" (Box 242)
          - IX "Christmas...And a New Year," drafts A-B, 2 folders (Box 242)
          - X "Progress Without" (Box 242)
          - XI "Personalities" (Box 242)
          - XII "The Great Test" (Box 242)
          - XIII "Undercurrents" (Box 242)
          - XIV "Prison Politics," draft A (Box 242)
          - XIV "Prison Politics," draft B (Box 243)
          - XV "The Death House" (Box 243)
          - XVI "The Mutual Welfare League" (Box 243)
          - XVII "Further Progress" (Box 243)
          - XVIII "Exit. Cummins" (Box 243)
          - XIX "Cross Currents" (Box 243)
          - XX "Superintendent Riley" (Box 243)
          - XXI "The First Attack," drafts A-B, 2 folders (Box 243)
          - XXII "At Great Meadow," drafts A-B, 2 folders (Box 243)
          - XXIII "Alarums and Excursions," drafts A-B, 2 folders (Box 244)
          - XXIV "Charles Becker" (Box 244)
          - XXV "The Confidential Agent" (Box 244)
          - XXVI "A Lull in the Storm'" drafts A-D, 4 folders (Box 244)
          - XXVII "The New Attack," drafts A-B, 2 folders (Box 244)
          - XXVIII "The Greatest Prison Problem" drafts A-C, 3 folders (Box 244)
          - XXIX "Introducing. Dr. Diedling," drafts A-D, 4 folders (Box 244)
          - XXX "The Blunderbuss," drafts A-C, 3 folders (Box 244)
          - XXXI "Preposterous Bosh," drafts A-D, 6 folders (Box 244)
          - XXXII "Cataline" ("Luther C. White"), drafts (Box 244)
          - XXXIII "The Artful Dodger," drafts A-B, 2 folders (Box 244)
          - XXXIV "Charles H. Johnson," drafts A-C, 3 folders (Box 244)
          - XXXV "Pecksniff" (Box 244)
          - XXXVI "Stacking the Cards," drafts A-B, 2 folders (Box 244)
          - XXXIII "The Grand Jury (1)," drafts A-F, 6 folders (Box 244)
          - XXXVIII "The Grand Jury (2)," drafts A-D, 4 folders (Box 245)
          - XXXIX "The Grand Jury (3)," drafts A-F, 6 folders (Box 245)
          - XL "Another Christmas" (Box 245)
          - XLI "Exit Riley," drafts A-B, 2 folders (Box 245)
          - XLII "Tony Marino" (Box 245)
          - XLIII "The Party of the Fifth Part," drafts A-C, 3 folders (Box 245)
          - XLIV "Carnegie Hall" (Box 245)
          - XLV "Jack, the Dropper" (Box 246)
          - XLVII "Warden Kirchwey," drafts A-B, 2 folders (Box 246)
          - XLVIII "The Trial" (Box 246)
          - XLIX "Victory and Vindication" (Box 246)
        - Salvaging Sing Sing, See Politics and Prisons
        - Society and Prisons (Yale Lectures: "The New Penology," 1916)
          - Notes (Box 246)
          - Draft A (Box 246)
          - Draft B (Box 246)
          - Galley proof (Box 246)
          - Reviews (Box 246)
        - Der Staat und die Gefangnisse: Einige Vorschlage fur eine neue Penelogie, undated (Box 246)
        - Within Prison Walls: Being a Narrative of Personal Experience During a Week of Voluntary Confinement in the State Prison at Auburn, New York, 1913
          - Table of Contents (Box 246)
          - I "Why I Went to Prison" (Box 246)
          - II "Sunday's Journal" (Box 246)
          - III "Monday Morning" (Box 246)
          - IV "Monday Afternoon" (Box 246)
          - V "The First Night" (Box 246)
          - VI "Tuesday Morning" (Box 247)
          - VII "Tuesday Afternoon and Evening" (Box 247)
          - VIII "Wednesday Morning and Afternoon" (Box 247)
          - IX "Wednesday Evening" (Box 247)
          - X "Thursday" (Box 247)
          - XI "Friday" (Box 247)
          - XII "The Jail" (Box 247)
          - XIII "A Night in Hell" (Box 247)
          - XIV "Sunday--The End" (Box 247)
          - XV "Cui Bono?" (Box 247)
          - Reviews (Box 247)
      - Diaries
        - (Vols. 66-69), 1877-1909; 4 folders (Box 247)
        - (Vols. 70-74), 1908-1926; 6 folders (Box 248)
      - Film scripts
        - "Bruised Humanity", circa 1920 (Box 248)
        - The Gray Brothers, circa 1920 (Box 248)
        - "Making Good", undated (Box 248)
        - "The New Commandment", undated (Box 248)
        - "A Prison Unprisoned", 1921 (Box 248)
        - The Right Way
          - Title page and contents (Box 248)
          - Prelude (Box 248)
          - Synopsis (Box 248)
          - I "A Poor Little Rich Boy" (Box 248)
          - II"A Poor Little Slum Boy" (Box 248)
          - III "First Lessons in Crime" (Box 248)
          - IV "Grown Up" (Box 248)
          - V "The Ball" (Box 248)
          - VI "The Sick Mother" (Box 248)
          - VII "Dishonor Among Thieves" (Box 248)
          - VIII "Cross Currents" (Box 248)
          - IX "Blanksburg" (Box 248)
          - X "Sowing the Wind" (Box 248)
          - XI "First Fruits" (Box 248)
          - XII "Easy the Descent" (Box 249)
          - XIII "Punishment" (Box 249)
          - XIV "Criminals" (Box 249)
          - XV "The Shadow of the Prison" (Box 249)
          - XVI "Jimmy's New Pal" (Box 249)
          - XVII "Release" (Box 249)
          - Interlude (Box 249)
          - XVIII "At Large" (Box 249)
          - XIX "The New Warden" (Box 249)
          - XX "The New Deal" (Box 249)
          - XXI "Jimmy's Return" (Box 249)
          - XXII "An Escape" (Box 249)
          - XXIII "At the Turn of the Road" (Box 249)
          - XXIV "The Den of Wu Fang' (Box 249)
          - XXV "Confession" (Box 249)
          - XXVI "The Desperate Chance" (Box 249)
          - XXVII "The Death-House" (Box 249)
          - XXVIII "Harvest" (Box 249)
          - Postlude (Box 249)
          - Suggested music (Box 249)
          - Film stills (Box 249)
          - Publicity (Box 249)
          - Reviews (Box 249)
        - "The Way Out" (Box 249)
      - Fragments, circa 1920 (Box 249)
      - Journals
        - "Tom Brown at Auburn Prison", 1913 (Box 249)
        - As Warden of Sing Sing Prison, 1914-1915 (Box 249)
        - "Tom Brown in the Navy" (Vol. 75), 1919 (Box 249)
        - European Travel (Vol. 76), 1873 (Box 249)
        - Around the World (Vol. 77), 1877-1879 (Box 249)
        - U.S. and European Travel (Vol. 78), 1822-1884 (Box 250)
        - European Travel (Vols. 79-81), 1894-1901; 3 folders (Box 250)
        - "Log of the Green Dragon" (Vol. 82), 1907 (Box 250)
        - European Travel (Vols. 83-86), 1911-1922; 4 folders (Box 250)
      - Notes
        - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 250)
        - On Music, undated (Box 250)
        - On Prisons, undated (Box 251)
        - On Travel, undated (Box 251)
      - Plays
        - Miscellaneous notes and drafts (Box 251)
        - [unidentified], undated (Box 251)
        - "Aladdin", undated (Box 251)
        - "About an American Soldier who Meets a French Maiden", circa 1920 (Box 251)
        - "Bombastes Furioso", undated (Box 251)
        - "Creatures of Impulse", circa 1920 (Box 251)
        - "Crooks", circa 1915 (Box 251)
        - "The Dawn: A Criminal Morality", circa 1915 (Box 251)
        - "Dorothy's Choice: A Romance of the Last Century", circa 1915 (Box 251)
        - "Faire Harvarde", circa 1884 (Box 251)
        - "Governor Hunts in Africa", circa 1910 (Box 251)
        - "In the Warden's Office", 1924 (Box 251)
        - "Pals", circa 1920 (Box 251)
        - "The Prison Unprisoned", circa 1920 (Box 251)
        - "The Speaker of the House", undated (Box 251)
        - "Which? A Criminal Morality", circa 1915 (Box 251)
      - Short Stories
        - "Action and Reaction", circa 1916 (Box 251)
        - "An Amateur Detective", undated (Box 251)
        - "Concerning Jimmy Gray", undated (Box 251)
        - "An Evening's Amusement", undated (Box 252)
        - "A Hobo Hold-Up", undated (Box 252)
        - "Jim Holcomb: A Simple Story", undated (Box 252)
        - "Making Good", undated (Box 252)
        - "My Friend the Burglar", undated (Box 252)
        - On Prison Council Employment Bureau, undated (Box 252)
        - "The Second Chance", undated (Box 252)
        - "Where the Accident Happened", undated (Box 252)
      - Travelogs
        - "The Adventures of Two Dragon-Flyers", circa 1910 (Box 252)
        - "Around the World Forty-Five Years Ago", 1922 (Box 252)
        - "A Glimpse of Japan", circa 1880 (Box 252)
        - "The Private Car," or "What We Saw in 'Dakoty' " (Vol. 87), 1882 (Box 252)
        - "The Sandwich Islands", undated (Box 252)
        - "The Tale of a Green Duck on the Susquehanna," Auburn Citizen, 1910; Notes and drafts; clippings; galley proof, revised; 3 folders (Box 252)
        - "Travel in Japan" (Box 252)
      - Verse, miscellaneous, 1900-1925 (Box 253)
    - Osborne Family (Unidentified)
      - Journal, Travel in the Western United States, 1880 (Box 253)
    - Pelham, Marianna
      - Article/essay, "May Day Walk and Coronation Fete", 1839 (Box 253)
    - Pennsylvania Reform School inmates
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 253)
    - Prisoner at Auburn State Prison
      - Article/essay, "The Malefactor's Attitude Toward Society", circa 1915 (Box 253)
    - Raleigh, Peter
      - Short story, "They Wait and Hope", undated (Box 253)
    - Rattigan, Charles F.
      - Biography, Hon. Thomas M. Osborne, Cayuga County's Candidate for Governor: A Brief Biographical Sketch and History of His Public Service (Vol. 88), 1910 (Box 253)
    - Richards, Dick
      - Journal, "Sing Sing Recollections" (Vols. 89-95), circa 1915; holograph and typescript; 2 folders (Box 253)
    - "Mother Runyon"
      - Report on Missouri State Prison, circa 1910 (Box 253)
    - Sellin, Thorstein
      - Biography, "Thomas Mott Osborne", circa 1930 (Box 253)
    - Storrow, Helen (Osborne)
      - Reminiscence, "On Thomas Mott Osborne", circa 1933 (Box 253)
    - Trask, Katrina
      - Miscellaneous, 1906-1915 (Box 253)
      - Film script, prospectus, "In the Vanguard: An Anti-War Drama", circa 1916 (Box 253)
    - Unidentified
      - Diaries (Vol. 96), 1846 (Box 253)
    - Warner, John DeWitt
      - Article/essay, "A Practical Income Tax", undated (Box 253)
    - Wood, Lewis
      - Pamphlet, "Sing Sing from the Inside", 1914; introduction by Thomas Mott Osborne, also "Compliments of Thomas Mott Osborne" printed on front cover (Box 253)
    - Woodward, N.F.
      - Miscellaneous, circa 1912 (Box 253)
    - White, Frank Marshall
      - Book, nonfiction, "A Five Year's Fight for an Underdog", circa 1920 (Box 253)
    - Wilsey, C.D.
      - Verse, "On Sing Sing Prison", 1915 (Box 253)
    - Wright, David
      See also Memorabilia: General: Wright, David (Box 344)
      - Miscellaneous, circa 1828 (Box 254)
      - Diaries, 1843 (Box 254)
      - Diaries (Vols. 40-44), 1839-1856 (Box 236)
      - Journal, "On Leaving Paris for the U.S.A.", 1939 (Box 236)
      - Reminiscences on the Civil War, circa 1886 (Box 254)
    - Wright, Martha Coffin
      - Diary, 1867-1874 (Box 236)
    - Wright, William Pelham, 1st Lt., Artillery
      - Diaries, Civil War: Peninsular Campaign to Gettysburg (Vols. 97-98), 1862-1863; 2 volumes (Box 254)
- Organization records
  - General
    - American Proportional Representation League, 1895-1916 (Box 254)
    - American-Scandinavian Foundation, 1962-1964 (Box 254)
    - Atlantic Council of the United States
      - Miscellaneous, 1955-1967 (Box 254)
      - Agenda, 1963-1966 (Box 254)
      - Finance, 1963-1966 (Box 254)
      - Memoranda, 1961-1967; 2 folders (Box 255)
      - Minutes, 1961-1967 (Box 255)
      - Newsletter, Atlantic Community News, 1963-1967 (Box 255)
      - Officers and sponsors, 1963-1965 (Box 255)
      - Policy statements, 1957-1967 (Box 255)
      - Reports, 1959-1967; 2 folders (Box 256)
    - The Atlantic Institute, 1961-1965 (Box 256)
    - Auburn, N.Y.
      - Miscellaneous, 1870-1939 (Box 256)
      - Auburn Barge Canal Project
        - General committee, 1920-1930 (Box 256)
        - Reference files, 1914-1919 (Box 257)
      - Chamber of Commerce, 1927-1932 (Box 257)
      - Charter Revision
        - Miscellaneous, 1904-1907 (Box 257)
        - Ledgers (Vols. 99-100), 1904-1905; 2 folders (Box 257)
      - Charter Revision Commission minutes (Vol. 101), 1903 (Box 257)
      - Charity Ball, 1930-1933 (Box 258)
      - City Charter, 1906; printed material (Box 258)
      - City Council, 1906-1930 (Box 258)
      - City Comptroller, 1928-1931 (Box 258)
      - City Manager, 1928-1931 (Box 258)
      - City Treasurer, 1904-1931 (Box 258)
      - Civil Service Commission, 1906-1911 (Box 258)
      - Board of Education, 1928 (Box 258)
      - Emergency Work Bureau, 1934-1935 (Box 258)
      - Finances, 1887-1928 (Box 258)
      - Mayor's annual messages (Vols. 102-104), 1903-1905; 3 volumes (Box 258)
      - Ordinances, circa 1905-1920 (Box 259)
      - Police Department annual reports, 1904-1930 (Box 259)
      - "A Proposed Auburn University", 1949; plan, 46 x 32 inches (Tube 2)
      - Public utilities
        - Auburn City Railway Company, 1890-1902 (Box 259)
        - Auburn and Northern Electric Railway Company, circa 1905 (Box 259)
        - East Genesee Street and Seward Avenue Railway, 1874-1879 (Box 259)
        - Light and gas companies, 1905-1930 (Box 259)
        - Road construction and maintenance, 1899-1931 (Box 259)
        - Water Board
          - Bids, 1901-1910 (Box 259)
          - Memorandums., circa 1904 (Box 259)
        - Water Department, 1904-1905; transcripts of hearings, Sections 1-11; 2 folders (Box 259)
    - Auburn Beethoven Club
      - Miscellaneous, 1900-1907 (Box 259)
      - Mailing lists, 1901 (Box 259)
      - Programs, 1898-1902 (Box 260)
    - Boy Scouts of America, Cayuga County Council, 1927-1932 (Box 260)
    - Cayuga County Memorial Building Committee, Incorporated, undated (Box 260)
    - Committee to Defend America by Aiding the Allies, 1940
      - Miscellaneous (Box 260)
      - Posters (2) and printing mat (1) (Oversize 1)
    - Dartmouth, Mass., Petition for Pauper Relief, 1786 (Box 260)
    - Declaration of Atlantic Unity
      - Miscellaneous, 1959-1966 (Box 260)
      - Agenda, 1956-1967 (Box 260)
      - Editorials, 1965-1967 (Box 260)
      - Finance, 1956-1966 (Box 260)
      - Memoranda, 1951-1967; 2 folders (Box 260)
      - Minutes, 1960-1967 (Box 261)
      - Policy statements, 1961-1967 (Box 261)
      - Printed matter, 1951-1963 (Box 261)
      - Reports, 1953-1967 (Box 261)
    - George Junior Republic, Freeville, N.Y.
      - Miscellaneous, 1897-1910 (Box 261)
      - Accounts, 1898-1910 (Box 261)
      - Articles of Incorporation, 1896 (Box 261)
      - Blueprints of buildings, circa 1905; also includes watercolor of schoolhouse (Oversize 12)
      - Constitution and By-Laws, 1898 (Box 261)
      - Finance, 1898-1921 (Box 261)
      - Flag, circa 1900 (Box 261)
      - Memoranda, 1903-1912 (Box 261)
      - Minutes, Executive Committee, 1898-1900; 2 folders (Box 261)
      - Minutes, Executive Committee, 1906-1913; 7 folders (Box 262)
      - Newsletter, The Junior Republic Citizen, I-VII (Vols. 105-106), 1898-1905; 2 volumes (Box 262)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1908-1912 (Box 262)
      - Printed matter, 1895-1932 (Box 263)
      - Register of students, 1895-1902 (Box 263)
      - Reminiscence by Citizen "200", circa 1918 (Box 263)
      - Reports
        - Miscellaneous, 1897-1911 (Box 263)
        - New York State Board of Charities, 1901-1908 (Box 263)
        - Student histories, 1898-1900 (Box 263)
        - Student president, circa 1910 (Box 263)
        - Superintendent, 1908 (Box 263)
        - Treasurer, 1901-1912 (Box 263)
        - Scrapbook, compiled by Thomas Mott Osborne (Vol. 107), 1897-1908 (Box 263)
        - Specifications and plans, 1898 (Box 263)
        - Statistics, student, 1896-1903 (Box 263)
        - Suits, student court, 1896-1907 (Box 263)
    - League of Nations Non-Partisan Committee, 1922-1923 (Box 264)
    - League to Abolish Capital Punishment, 1916-1931 (Box 264)
    - Massachusetts Anti-Slavery Society, 1843; circular letter on William Lloyd Garrison's Liberator (Box 264)
    - Mutual Art Society of New York, 1914 (Box 264)
    - National Crime Commission, 1925 (Box 264)
    - New York Peace Society, 1914 (Box 264)
    - New York State
      - Miscellaneous, circa 1930 (Box 264)
      - Bureau of Municipal Information reports, 1928-1935; 4 folders (Box 264)
      - Conservation Council, 1935-1951 (Box 265)
      - Conservation Department
        - Miscellaneous, 1933-1961 (Box 265)
        - Memoranda and printed matter, 1933-1967 (Box 265)
      - Crime Commission, 1928-1954 (Box 265)
      - Department of Correction, 1936 (Box 265)
      - Fish and Game Commission, 1911 (Box 265)
      - National Guard, 1924 (Box 265)
      - Public Service Commission
        - Miscellaneous, 1909-1931 (Box 265)
        - Reports, 1906-1911 (Box 265)
        - Printed matter, 1907-1910 (Box 265)
    - New York State Conference of Charities, 1916 (Box 265)
    - New York State Conference of Mayors, 1914-1936 (Box 265)
    - New York State Conference of Religion, 1898-1900 (Box 265)
    - New York State Temperance Society, 1843 (Box 266)
    - "Old Soldiers" (World War I), 1931-1938; annual dinners guest registers and seating plans (Box 266)
    - Osborne Relief Association, 1905; finance (Box 266)
    - The Osborne School
      - Miscellaneous, 1911-1920 (Box 266)
      - Blueprints of buildings, 1912 (Tube 2)
      - Diagrams: Furniture, 1912 (Oversize 2)